[roaring]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words…
are called…
Hunters.
[theme song playing]
Come on! You can’t be serious!
[laughing]
Oh, I am quite serious.
The winners will pass the Exam
and earn the title of Hunter.
CAN'T WIN x BUT x CAN'T LOSE
[narrator] The nine remaining applicants,
Gon,
Killua,
Kurapika,
Leorio,
Pokkle, Bodoro,
Gittarackur,
Hanzo
and Hisoka,
having passed the Fourth Phase,
head to the site
of the Final Phase of the Exam.
[Netero] Well, gentlemen.
Everyone rested up?
Good.
Now then. The Hunter Exam Committee
runs this hotel.
So, I want all of you
to make yourselves at home
until the battles have concluded.
For the Final Phase of the Hunter Exam
you’ll be competing
in a one-on-one tournament.
[Leorio] Hold on a second.
So only the last person standing passes?
[Netero] No.
You only need one win to pass this phase.
Just one?
Wait. So, in this tournament…
See, it’s the winners who will drop away
and the losers
who will advance to the next round.
Which means
the person who finishes at the top
will not pass.
Make sense to everyone?
You’re saying that only one person
will fail the Exam.
Exactly.
Here is the bracket we’ve put together.
Impressive, yes?
You see under this format
every competitor has at least two chances
to win a round.
Yeah but some people
get five chances to win,
like Numbers 294 and 405.
Couldn’t you have used
a more balanced bracket?
[thoughtful grunt]
Now, that’s a fair question.
This bracket was carefully assembled
based on each
of your individual performances
throughout the Hunter Exam.
To put it simply,
those whose performances
were rated highly,
will have the most chances to win.
[Killua] I’m not convinced.
Could you explain exactly
how you scored our performances?
Hmm...
[yells] No!
[Killua] Why not?
[Netero laughs]
I can’t say because your scores
are classified.
I can’t reveal your actual scores.
However, I can explain
the criteria we used.
We start with the basics.
There are three categories.
There’s physical strength,
mental acuity
and lastly, overall impression.
When judging physical strength, we rely on
an aggregate of agility, flexibility,
endurance,
and perception.
For mental acuity the aggregate
consists of
resilience, adaptability, judgment,
and of course, creativity.
But these are only reference points.
After all, every last one of you
was strong enough in mind and body
to reach the Final Phase.
We’re most concerned
with your overall impression.
This refers to any intangible factors
that defy basic categorization.
[chuckles]
Think of it as our way
of assessing your potential as a Hunter.
We round out our assessment by
incorporating the opinions of your peers.
There you have it.
[Killua] Based on my performance,
I should be ranked higher.
Do I have less potential than Gon?
The rules of the battle
are really quite simple.
Weapons are allowed,
cheating is forbidden,
and if your opponent admits defeat,
you win.
However!
If you kill your opponent,
you will be disqualified
without hesitation.
And if that happens, the Exam ends
and the remaining applicants pass.
Got it?
[Masta]
Let the Final Phase of the Exam begin!
[Hanzo cracking his wrists]
The first match:
Hanzo versus Gon.
Enter!
[trumpets playing fanfare]
I’m Masta.
I’ll be serving as referee
for the tournament.
Good luck. Both of you.
Hey. Good to see you again.
You were the one who was tailing me around
during the Fourth Phase.
You noticed that, did you?
Naturally.
I assume that each of the Examiners
was assigned an Examinee to follow.
Well, I’m sure I wasn’t the only one
who noticed.
I had no idea!
Oh, I definitely noticed.
I noticed, but didn’t think
it was worth mentioning.
Uh. Yeah…
How was I supposed to know?
I’m very grateful.
You recognized my talent
and my rank improved as a result.
But no surprise there, really.
Sure, but...
[Hanzo] Now, moving on.
I have a question for you.
What is it?
[Hanzo] We can only win
if our opponent surrenders.
Correct?
[Hanzo]
Knocking them unconscious doesn’t count.
No TKOs either?
Right. Those are the rules.
Hmm...
I see.
Well. This one might prove difficult.
He looks tough.
but we should be pretty even
in strength and speed.
I’ve just gotta keep him on the move
‘til I see an opening.
Now, time to start.
All right, Gon. Get him!
I wonder how he’ll do against Hanzo.
Begin!
I’ll keep some distance.
[gasps]
You must think you’re
pretty quick on your feet, don’t you?
I’ll give you that.
[choking sounds]
Not half bad for a little kid.
[scoffs]
I could have dodged that no problem.
[choking sounds]
Now if this were a regular match,
I’d already be declared the winner.
C’mon, pull yourself together.
-[bones crackling]
-[Gon grunts]
You must feel awful.
I hit you hard enough
to bounce your brain around your skull.
You get it? You don’t stand a chance.
Just give up
and spare yourself the trouble.
[straining]
No way!
-[Gon coughing]
-Think hard about it.
Surrender now
and you’ll have another chance.
But being stubborn
isn’t gonna get you anywhere.
So just give up.
That’s never gonna happen!
[groans]
-[Gon groans weakly]
-Say it.
[Gon groans]
[Gon groans in pain]
Gon! Don’t push it!
You still have other fights!
-So just--
-[Kurapika] Leorio!
If you were in Gon’s position,
would you give up?
Hell, no, I wouldn’t!
He thinks he’s so tough…
[Kurapika] Gon feels the same.
Come on! I know that!
But it doesn’t look like
he has much of a choice!
My point exactly.
But I understand.
-[Gon grunts]
-[Kurapika and Leorio wince]
[grunts]
Surrender, Gon! This is suicide!
[Menchi] This is unbelievable.
The Chairman’s mean streak
is really in a class by itself!
Wait, what do you mean?
No applicant who’s made it
all the way to here,
is going to simply give up a fight
that easily.
[Buhara] That’s true.
-[Gon groans]
-This fight isn’t just peculiar.
A system like this is completely crazy.
The kid’s in real danger.
[groaning quietly in pain]
HUNTER GLOSSARY
[Leorio smirks]
HANZO
[blows]
[thud]
[Leorio growling quietly]
Three whole hours? Damn.
Look. He can’t even vomit anymore.
Now get up.
[Leorio growls] Enough already!
I’m gonna kill you, hear me?
Pick on someone your own size!
If you can’t handle it,
you’d better leave.
It’s only going to get worse.
What the hell did you say?
There’ll be no interference
in a one-on-one match.
Stay back.
If you try to help him in any way,
Gon will be instantly disqualified!
[Gon] It’s okay.
Leorio…
This is...
this is nothing.
Really.
[growls quietly]
I can still fight him.
[frustrated growl]
[Gon grunts]
-I’ll break your arm.
-[Gon gasps]
[groaning quietly]
I’m not kidding.
Now say it.
Say you surrender.
-[yells] Never!
-[thud]
[Gon groaning quietly]
[groans in pain]
He actually broke it.
[Hanzo] There.
Now you won’t be able
to use your left arm anymore.
[grinding teeth in frustration]
[Leorio] Don’t try to stop me, Kurapika.
If that bastard does anything else,
Gon will fail the exam.
'Cause I won’t be able to stop myself.
[Kurapika] Me?
You think I’ll stop you?
Don’t worry.
There’s no chance of that.
[Hanzo] I’m sure you’re in too much pain
to listen,
but hear this.
I’m a descendant of a clandestine group
called the shinobi.
From the day I was born,
I’ve been subjected
to intensive training
in order to master
the special art of ninpo.
For the past 18 years
I’ve tirelessly trained my body
and honed my technique.
By the time I was your age,
I had already killed.
[scoffs] Not like it’s that big a deal.
[Hanzo] At this point in time
you have no hope
of defeating me in combat.
I’m being nice.
So just admit defeat--
[grunts in pain]
[Gon groans in pain]
Dammit!
Between the pain and you blabbing
I don’t know what cleared my head up more!
Hell yeah!
Atta boy!
Now kick him while he’s down
and he’s finished!
If you’re eighteen,
then you’re just six years older than me.
Besides this isn’t a battle
to see who’s stronger.
It’s to see who’s willing
to throw in the towel first.
I let you kick me because I wanted to.
You’re a liar!
[Hanzo] You must be confused.
That was not a warning.
It was a direct order.
Was it too hard for you to understand?
I’m quite happy to break it down for you.
I’ll cut off your legs,
so that they can’t be reattached.
A permanent injury
should open up your eyes
to the current situation.
But before we must resort to such things,
I want to hear you surrender.
[Gon] Well, that’s a problem.
I don’t want to have my legs cut off
but I don’t want to surrender, either.
How ‘bout we find
a different way to fight?
[yells] What the hell?
Have you not been paying attention?
-[Hisoka chuckling]
-[Bodoro laughing]
Oh, pardon me.
Are you really making demands?
You messin’ with me?
I’m seriously about to cut your legs off!
You do what you want but I won’t give up!
[growling in anger]
Besides if you cut my legs off,
I’ll probably just bleed to death.
[Hanzo] What?
Mister Masta?
He’d be disqualified for that, right?
Uh... Yes.
See?
And that’d be bad for the both of us.
So, let’s think of a better way.
[angered growling]
[growling loudly]
[Kurapika chuckles] I think Gon is okay.
He’s in control now.
He’s just so damn stubborn!
But he’s also convincing
to Hanzo and the rest of us.
Impressive.
[Killua] What the hell is this?
Nothing’s changed.
I mean, it’s not like
Gon’s gotten any stronger.
His arm is still broken and everything!
But what happened to the mood in here?
It was so tense a second ago.
Why did it get so much lighter?
[angered growling]
[Hanzo] I see you’re not getting it,
so I’ll try again.
Die and you’ll never get another chance.
If I kill you right here and now,
I only need to come back
and take the Exam again next year.
We are not on equal footing!
[Killua] He’s right, Gon.
You might have the edge
when it comes to brains
but you don’t have the combat skills
he does.
That’s not something
you can make up for right now.
In the end, it all comes down to ability.
[Leorio grunts]
[grunting]
What’s wrong?
It’s just a stupid sentence!
Think! Give up
and you can still try again next year!
Is your pride truly
all that you care about?
Even more than your life?
Is it worth dying for?
[grunts]
I’m gonna go see my dad.
Your dad?
See, my dad is a Hunter.
So, I’m gonna become a Hunter
exactly like he is
and then I’ll be able to meet him!
I know I’ll find him someday.
But... I feel like if I surrender now,
I’m never gonna find him!
So, I won’t give up.
Surrender...
or you will die.
So, logic had nothing to do with it.
Fine. You win.
I give up, okay?
I’m not allowed to kill you.
And I just can’t think of another way
to force you to surrender.
So, I’ll take my chances
in the next round.
Well, I can’t accept that.
No fair!
We both have to come up with some way
that we can have a proper match!
[Hanzo sighs]
Why am I not surprised?
[yells]
You just said you would never surrender,
so what the hell is the point of that,
you idiot?
The point is that I don’t want
to win like this, okay?
Then what do you suggest?
Let’s work together and figure it out!
So, in other words...
I’ve already given up the match
but you want me to continue fighting
and try to beat you again right?
But first we have to work together
to find a way you can win,
so you feel good about your victory.
Is that right?
Yeah!
[yells] Moron!
Hey, referee.
I lose, so move on to the next match.
Understood, sir.
But I’d like to say something first.
Whenever he wakes up,
he’ll probably decline his advancement.
And as we’ve all seen,
he can be incredibly stubborn.
Only one person fails this round, right?
So, if Gon is disqualified,
wouldn’t that render
the rest of our upcoming fights
completely meaningless?
[narrator] With Hanzo’s concession,
Gon’s victory has been assured.
The Final Phase
that will determine
the single failing applicant
has only just begun.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time:
"Baffling Turn x Of x Events!"
[Gon gibers]
[Killua]
They stuck a needle in Gon, too?